JHENIELLE FRANCIS

+44 7585151122 | jheniellefran@gmail.com | London, UK, SE10
Portfolio jhfran.github.io | GitHub github.com/jhfran
LinkedIn linkedin.com/in/jhenielle-francis

PERSONAL STATEMENT

PRINCE2 Practitioner with an MSc in Applied Data Science and Statistics. Passionate about data science, machine learning and building models that translate data into insights and recommendations. Self-starter and fast learner with an analytical mindset and experience in data visualization, statistical modelling and machine learning. Excellent problem-solving skills, communication skills and ability to present technical information to both technical and non-technical stakeholders. Interested in data scientist roles.

SKILLS

R / Python / SQL / Machine learning (supervised ML and unsupervised ML) / Statistics / Statistical modelling / Visualizing data in R, Python and Tableau / Data querying with Python and SQL / Data analysis / Data wrangling / Exploratory data analysis / Model Development / Model Evaluation / Jupyter Notebook / IBM Cloud / Presentations / Reports / Project management / Client management / Stakeholder management

EDUCATION

Master's Degree in Applied Data Science and Statistics (Distinction)

University of Exeter

Sept 2019 - Sept 2020

- Awarded Dean's Commendation for Exceptional Performance
- Dissertation Project: <u>Utilising machine learning to investigate electrical activity in ventricular myocytes</u>
- Modules included: Applications of Data Science and Statistics, Working with Data, Advanced Topics in Statistics, Advanced Statistical Modelling, Data Governance and Ethics, Statistical Modelling in Space and Time, Engaging with Research

Bachelor's Degree in Psychology

Northwestern University

Sept 2011 - Mar 2015

o Modules included: Statistical Methods in Psychology, Single Variable Calculus, Field Studies in Public Health

Associate Degree in Natural Sciences

Hampton High School

Sept 2004 - Jun 2011

* Grade [I] is the highest grade achievable

- o 7 CAPEs (A Level equivalent) | Grades I-II including Chemistry [I], Pure Mathematics [II], Communication Studies [II]
- 8 CSECs (GCSE equivalent) | Grades I II including English [I], Mathematics [I], Accounting [I]

CERTIFICATIONS & COURSES

IBM Data Science Professional Certificate | Coursera | Ongoing

- o Pathway to Data Analytics | *Q-Step Centre* | March 2020
- o Data Science A-Z: Real-Life Data Science Exercises | *Udemy* | May 2019
- PRINCE2 Foundation in Project Management | AXELOS | Feb 2017
- o PRINCE2 Registered Practitioner in Project Management | *AXELOS* | Feb 2017 Feb 2022

WORK EXPERIENCE

Connector InternBuddyHub C.I.C.

Dec 2017 - Sept 2019 May 2017 - Dec 2017

Award-winning technology startup utilising a subscription business model to combat loneliness and social isolation

- Managed 25+ client accounts, 50+ volunteers and the relationships between them
- o Onboarded and interviewed all clients (Senior members) and volunteer befrienders (Buddies)
- Matched clients with their Buddies by utilising smart technology and a personalised touch
- Assisted the CEO in her product owner role
- o Worked with developers to aid in technology platform development in an agile environment
- Optimised the onboarding and interviewing processes
- Carried out research and operational, strategic and growth tasks to aid in business model development

Freelance Recruiter Nov 2016 – Apr 2017

Self-Employed

- Developed recruitment and staffing strategies in collaboration with hiring managers and management
- Pre-screened applications, shortlisted candidates and assisted with interviews

Temporary Administrator

Oct 2016

NPW Gifts

Giftware company designing, sourcing and selling products to European and North American retailers

- Provided administrative support to 5 employees to ensure tasks were completed by the set deadlines
- Managed and organised bookings, the company inbox, DPD collections and e-mail archives

Nanny Jan 2016 – Aug 2016

Private Family

- Cared for three children of ages one, four and seven
- Balanced and re-worked each child's schedule to fit in all activities and prioritised when necessary

Intern Jan 2015 – Mar 2015

The Danny Did Foundation

Non-profit organisation with a mission to increase SUDEP awareness and reduce the risks associated with seizures

- Created, planned and managed an international educational project, furthering the foundation's brand
- Served as an ambassador at Northwestern University, events and fundraisers

Human Resources Assistant

Summers 2011 - 2013

Mid-Island Corporate Services Limited

Small accounting firm specialising in accounting, business advisory, tax consultation and payroll processes

- Optimised employee onboarding & training processes
- Assisted with full cycle recruitment and contributed to final hiring decisions

ADDITIONAL IT SKILLS